{"Topic": "Buddhism", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "The largest Buddhist temple in the world is located in", "op1": "India", "op2": "Indonesia", "op3": "Japan", "op4": "China", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The earliest Buddhist literature which deal with the stories of the various births of Buddha are", "op1": "Venaya pitakas", "op2": "Sutta pitakas", "op3": "Abhidhamma pitakas", "op4": "Jatakas", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Among the following who was the personal physician of Gautam Buddha?", "op1": "Sushruta", "op2": "Charak", "op3": "Jeevaka", "op4": "Nagarjuna", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The Buddha delivered his first sermon, known as 'Turning of the wheel of law' at?", "op1": "Sanchi", "op2": "Sarnath", "op3": "Sravasti", "op4": "Bodh Gaya", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In Buddhism, what does Patimokkha stand for?", "op1": "A description of Mahayana", "op2": "A description of Hinayana", "op3": "The rules of the Sangha", "op4": "The questions of King Menander", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Where is Lumbini, the birth place of Gautama Buddha located?", "op1": "Nepal", "op2": "Bihar", "op3": "Bhutan", "op4": "Sikkim", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who among the following was contemporary of Gautam Buddha?", "op1": "Nagarjuna", "op2": "Kanishka", "op3": "Kautilya", "op4": "Mahavir", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Where did Buddha attain Parinirvana?", "op1": "Bodh Gaya", "op2": "Kushinagara", "op3": "Rajgriha", "op4": "Vaishali", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The monk who influenced Ashoka to embrace Buddhism was", "op1": "Sarnath", "op2": "Bodhgaya", "op3": "Kapilvastu", "op4": "Rajgriha", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Mention the place where Buddha attained enlightment", "op1": "Pakistan", "op2": "Turkey", "op3": "Afghanistan", "op4": "Iran", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which of the following countries were Buddha's idols disfigured and removed a few years back?", "op1": "A place where intellectual debates among Buddhist mendicants took place", "op2": "A place where animals were kept", "op3": "A place where weapons were stored", "op4": "A place to sleep", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What was the Kutagarashala - literally, a hut with a pointed roof?", "op1": "Buddha's calling of the Earth to watch over Mara and to prevent Mara from disturbing his meditation", "op2": "Buddha's calling fo the Earth to witness his purity and chastity despite the temptations of Mara", "op3": "Buddha's reminder to his followers that they all arise from the Earth and finally dissolve into the Earth, and thus this life is transitory", "op4": "Both the statements (a) and (b) are correct in this context", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Lord Buddha's image is sometimes shown with the hand gesture called Bhumisparsha Mudra. It symbolizes", "op1": "1 only", "op2": "2 and 3 only", "op3": "1 and 3 only", "op4": "1, 2 and 3", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "With reference to the history of ancient India, which of the following was/were common to both Buddhism and Jainism?", "op1": "Arunachal Pradesh", "op2": "Sikkim", "op3": "Uttarakhand", "op4": "Himachal Pradesh", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "ect the correct answer using the codes given below:", "op1": "Panini", "op2": "Alara Kalama", "op3": "Kapila", "op4": "Patanjali", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which State is the Buddhist site Tabo Monastery located?", "op1": "Viharas", "op2": "Pitakas", "op3": "Stupas", "op4": "Chaityas", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who was the teacher of Gautama Buddha?"}, {"Question": "In which language were Buddhist literatures written?", "op1": "Sanskrit", "op2": "Prakrit", "op3": "Hindi", "op4": "Pali", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which country has the highest number of Buddhists in the world?", "op1": "India", "op2": "Japan", "op3": "China", "op4": "Indonesia", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Vaishak Purnima or Buddha Purnima is celebrated every year to mark which of the following events of Buddha's life?", "op1": "Birth", "op2": "Nirvana (Enlightenment)", "op3": "Parinirvana (Death)", "op4": "All of the above", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Buddha Vihars were used for :", "op1": "2 is correct", "op2": "1 and 3 are correct", "op3": "1, 2 and 4 are correct", "op4": "1 and 4 are correct", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Mahayan sect of Budhism emerged during the reign of :", "op1": "Ashoka", "op2": "Kanishka", "op3": "Samudra Gupta", "op4": "Harsha", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which country is the statue of 'Leshan Giant Buddha' located?", "op1": "Thailand", "op2": "China", "op3": "Japan", "op4": "Indonesia", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is the Dhamekh Stupa located?", "op1": "Sarnath, Uttar Pradesh", "op2": "Sanchi, Madhya Pradesh", "op3": "Gangtok, Sikkim", "op4": "Gaya, Bihar", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which state in India has the largest number of Buddhists?", "op1": "Himachal Pradesh", "op2": "Jammu and Kashmir", "op3": "Maharashtra", "op4": "Bihar", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "During whose reign was the third Buddhist Council held?", "op1": "Ashoka", "op2": "Kanishka", "op3": "Harsha", "op4": "Samudragupta", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following contain Buddhist teachings?", "op1": "Chaityas", "op2": "Jatakas", "op3": "Purvas", "op4": "Tripitakas", "Answer": 2}]}